北爱尔兰 1974年
NORTHERN IRELAND 1974
数十年的内乱 终酿成武装冲突
DECADES OF CIVIL UNREST HAVE EXPLODED INTO ARMED CONFLICT
贝尔法斯特
他们来了
Now they come.
快点 小伙子们
Come on, boys.
- 该死的有小孩 - 别闹了 帕特里克
- Damn brats. - Don't tease, Patrick.
不会这么巧吧
Just what was missing.
捡起来 给哥哥道歉
Pick yourself up and say sorry to your brother.
- 别瞎弄  - 要迟到了
I dont want this. You are late.
见鬼 快点 !
Come on, damn it!
别管了!
Leave it alone!
快他妈跑啊 见鬼
Hurry up, dammit!
快上车!
Ind!
- 开车 操 - 快!
- Drive, dammit! - Drive!
多尼戈尔郡
慢点 该死的!
Slow down, dammit!
《圣罚之地》
- 你真是个鬼东西 芬巴  - 什么 文尼?
- You are a sneaky prankster, Finbar. - What, Vinny?
我看到你在搞什么鬼了
多 尼 戈 尔 西 岸
I can see what you're up to.
看不见靶子怎么瞄准 快把它们从顶子上挪回来
I can't hit when I can't see them. Move them back up.
风太大 我啥也听不见
I can't hear anything because of the wind.
好借口
It's good with you.
你要认为我搞鬼的话 奥谢警官 那我就要生气了
If you suggest I'm cheating, Officer O'Shea, I'm going to be angry.
打赌就得公平
A bet must be fair.
你到底是要继续叨逼叨 还是开完枪后照旧认输?
Are you going to stand and whine or shoot and lose as usual?
瞄准准
Clean me up.
- 加油  - 鬼东西
- Come on. - Cunning shenanigans.
- 谢啦 - 又骗我钱 混球
- Thanks. - You pick me, you scumbag.
你今天还干了些啥
What did you do today besides feed the cat -
除了喂猫、看《格列佛游记》和《小小高球手》之外
- and ponder the sanity of Gulliver and the Little Putters?
《格列佛游记》读完了 现在在读俄罗斯作家陀思妥耶夫斯基的作品
I finished "Gulliver's Travels". Now it's Dostoevsky, Russian writer.
不了解 阿加莎的书（侦探小说)更适合我
I probably don't know him. Agatha Christie is more my cup of tea.
- 我们要上哪去? - 上班去
- Where are we going? - I am out of office.
贝利夫人告诉我
Mrs. Bailey tells -
小镇的欢迎标志牌不见了
- that the town's welcome sign has disappeared.
知道我平时都在干些啥活了吧
Now you can see what real work is.
简直一团糟啊
That's pretty fair.
- 红棕色 - 酒红色
- Reddish brown. - Burgundy red.
- 勃艮第(葡萄酒)红? - 没错
- Burgundy red? - Yes.
肯定是哪个疯子开车失控
Some madman must have lost control.
- 或是个酒鬼 - 也许是脑子有毛病
- Or a drunkard. - He must be stupid in the head.
要不要去镇上找找这个疯子?
Should you be looking for a crazy person in the city?
好啊 下午茶的时候我就能逮住这家伙
Yes. I'll probably have him around teatime.
我脑后有眼睛能看见你
I can feel your eyes in the back of my neck.
丽塔 我非常确定
Rita, I'm sure -
亚当甚至会把夏娃卖给你
- that Adam would have exchanged his Eve with you -
一旦他看到这块地方
- if he saw this place.
- 总得有点事儿干 - 花儿真好看
- It is healthy to have a hobby. - They will probably decorate.
拿去装饰餐桌的
For the table decoration.
就看你接不接受我的晚餐邀请了
You would know that if you had accepted my invitations.
布兰登怎么样了?
How is Brendan?
还是老样子
He doesn't get better.
有你这样的好女子 他一定会好好活着的
With such a lovely young woman like you, he'll probably stick around.
巴特.麦吉尼斯.班特里
爆炸造成包括三名儿童在内的六人死亡 据信为北爱共和军主使
但目前暂无人声称对此事件负责 如有知情者 请与警方联系
班特里港
班特里社区贡献奖 1974年
好了 大家安静
Quietly.
下面一位我怎么称赞都不为过
I can't say enough about Next Live.
他对本镇贡献良多 且多才多艺
He has done more for the city than we deserve. A man of many talents.
或许我们可以请他上台为我们表演
And maybe we can entice him to perform for us.
巴特.麦吉尼斯 能为我们献上一曲吗?
Bart McGuinness, will you grace us with a song?
你们不会想听一个老家伙唱歌的 就连我家里人都听不下去
You don't want to hear an old junkie sing. My own flesh and blood intersect.
我希望我能
在卡里克弗格斯
只在巴利格兰安眠
我会游过那
深深的海洋
游过那深深的海洋 去寻找我的爱人
起来 跟上
Come on.
- 干脆点 就在这开枪吧 - 继续走 往左走
- Can't you just shoot me here? - Continue. It's her on the left.
这里不错
It's nice here.
向右走两步
Two steps to the right.
挖吧
Grav.
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
一定要死在这里的话 至少告诉我这是哪儿
If I am to be laid to rest here, I want to know where I am.
多尼戈尔
Donegal.
多尼戈尔 国家的另一端
Donegal at the other end of the country.
"被遗忘的郡" 多么恰当的名字
The Forgotten County. How appropriate.
- 你就是靠这个谋生的吗? - 够深了 出来
- Is this how you make a living? - That's deep enough. Get up.
跪下
Down on your knees.
我的主啊
You almighty.
瞧瞧这些树
All those trees.
您太忙了
You have been busy.
跪下
Down on your knees.
双手抱头
Hands behind the head.
你有一分钟时间 想说什么就说吧
You have one minute. Say what you want.
就算乞求上苍 事情也不会改变
You're welcome to beg. It makes neither off nor on.
我无需乞求 迟早有这一刻的
I don't need to beg. I knew this day would come.
甚至比我预计的要晚
It took longer than expected.
仿佛已经隔世
It's been forever.
我少时年轻气盛
I had a violent temper as a youth.
杀过几个人
I have many guilty consciences.
大错已铸成
I knew there was no turning back…
我亦无路可退
after what I had done.
直到有一天 我觉得我不该再那样
But one day I decided that what was left of my fading soul...
虚度年华
should not go to waste.
所以 不知怎地
So somehow -
我浪子回头 回归公序良俗
- I blew away the dark cloud and became a good citizen.
并且为大家做了些力所能及的事
I did what I could for people.
您瞧 这就是我这样人的结局了
You see, this is where it ends for people like us.
曝尸荒野
On a windswept moorland.
试着做点好事吧 在你也大限将至之前
Try to do something good before you end up here yourself.
时日无多了
Time is running out.
我已时日无多
少年们啊
将我放平吧
- 有什么问题吗 凯文? - 没有
- Any problems, Kev? - No.
你是同性恋吗 罗伯特
Are you gay, Robert?
- 听听你放的音乐就知道 - 你是不是弱智 凯文?
- Your music suggests that. - Are you stupid, Kev?
瞧瞧你穿的靴子就知道
Your boots suggest you are stupid.
一瞧就知道你会弄得一团糟
I don't dare think about the mess you made.
这首穆迪蓝调的单曲太棒了
An excellent 45 with the Moody Blues.
借我了
I'll borrow it.
"体弱者因纵欲而早夭"
"Indulgence leads to an early death for the weak."
谁说的? (爱尔兰大诗人)叶慈?
Who is it? Yeats?
我老妈说的
My mother.
- 谁啊? - 是我 马奎夫人
- Who is it? - Just me.
芬巴 罗比说你要来 我正在做你喜欢的糕点
Finbar, how are you? I made the scones you love.
- 加樱桃的?  - 加葡萄干 我记得是葡萄干
- With cherries? - Raisins. I thought they were raisins.
那就对了 你比我更了解我
That's it. You know me better than I do myself.
我想也是
I thought so.
- 你把它们带来了?  - 是啊
Are you taking them with you? You always do that.
你总是这么贴心
早上好啊 美女 热的吗?
Good morning, dammit, you beauties. Are they hot?
- 嘿嘿嘿 懂不懂礼貌 - 这就是他
- Behave yourself. - There he is.
西部快枪手
The fastest hand in the west.
- 那是个都柏林男孩 - 现在的年轻人呐
- It was a Dublin boy. - The youth today!
- 还好吧? - 还行 你呢?
- How are you? - What about you?
- 谢谢 - 新的收藏?
- Thanks. - Something new for the collection?
我把它当作酬劳 奥赖利家族的
I took it as payment from the O'Reilly clan.
是个墨西哥人画的
It was painted by a Mexican.
这玩意儿在美国老风靡了 估值远超他们的欠账
Apparently it's all the rage in America. And worth much more than they owed.
可惜卖不出去 只能留着物归原主
Too bad you can't sell it back to its rightful owner.
我得先盘个存 下周给你找个活儿
I'll have to keep an eye out. I have something for you in a week's time.
给他吧
Give it to him.
活儿都给他
The job. Give him all of them.
我思虑良久
I've given it a lot of thought.
自打玛格丽特走后
I've made so many bad choices ever since Margaret died.
我总在思量之前的所作所为
我能做的不止是打打杀杀 我想让人看到这点
I can do more than this. And people need to see that.
那 你想向世界展示自己?
So what is it that you are passionate about showing the world?
可你只会打打杀杀啊
This is the only thing you can do.
我还可以弄个花圃
I could plant a garden.
- 花圃? - 是的
- A garden? - Yes.
所以你忍心丢我一个人在这儿吐口水吗?
So you just leave me in the lurch with that slobber?
谢了
So.
你会想我吗?
Are you going to miss me?
当然 就像脑袋上的包总得挠挠
Yes, as much as a hole in the head.
- 你 买种子? - 是的 帕特
- Frog? - Yes.
- 你会种地? - 不会 之前没弄过
- You don't usually buy seeds. - No.
- 你确定要买? - 是的 有些啥?
- Are you sure? - Yes. Do you have some or what?
我有...
I have...
豌豆、卷心菜 还有胡萝卜和其他小菜
horse beans, cabbage. There are also carrots and other trifles.
我想弄个自己的小花园
I want to plant my own garden.
种点作物 比如金灿灿的麦子
A little poplar, maybe golden rice.
我喜欢你这里金黄色的麦浪
Like the yellow wave you have out there.
种地要会除草 芬巴
Golden rice is a weed, Finbar.
我不懂 但我可以找个老师
I had no idea. I could use a teacher.
- 味道如何? - 我喜欢 美食还有陪伴
- Does it taste good enough? - I enjoy both the food and the company.
你的妻子做饭好吃吗? 是叫玛格丽特 对吗?
Was your wife good at cooking? It was Margaret, wasn't it?
- 对不起 我不是故意提…  - 不不不 没关系
- Sorry... - It doesn't matter.
只是 好久没听人提起她的名字了
It's just been so long since anyone said her name.
玛格丽特
Margaret.
她总爱实验新鲜玩艺儿
She was always experimenting.
她烤了个蛋糕 好久之前的事了
She baked a cake... It's been a long time.
她在里面放了苹果和坚果
She put apples and nuts in it.
还放了点肉桂 很独特的味道
And a little bit of cinnamon. I have never tasted anything like it.
- 听起来很美味 - 不 见鬼 超可怕的
- It sounds delicious. - No, damn it. It was terrifying.
我说过 闻所未闻的味道
Like I said, I've never tasted anything like it.
谢天谢地 她再也没这么做过
Fortunately, I never got around to it again.
当时是在都柏林吗?
Was it in Dublin?
对 是的
And.
每天我都会路过 她工作的书店
Every day I passed by the bookstore where she worked.
在去工厂的路上 你懂的 她真的很喜欢书
On the way to the factory. How she loved those books though.
- 她吸引了我的关注 - 我真希望能见到她
- She got me interested. - I wish I had met her.
她对我很好 就像你一样
She was too good for me. Just like you.
我去看看他
I look right at him.
嘿 莫娅
Hey Moya.
如果鱼上钩了 千万要小心 渔线会割伤手
If you get a red skull on the hook, be careful because the line can cut your hand.
来 用这个
Here. Use it here.
这样就好了
Such.
你想钓什么? 金鱼吗?
What are you hoping to capture? A goldfish?
- 把它带回家 起个名字叫戈尔迪 - 鱼没有情感
- Take it home and call it Goldie. - A fish doesn't like one.
我死去的老爹说过 不要枉费时间在不爱你的事物身上
My dead father said you shouldn't love those who don't love you.
- 很有道理 - 有人叫我去吃晚饭
- It may be true. - I was told to catch dinner.
咬钩了
You have bite.
拉紧渔线 拉紧渔线
Give it some string.
不
No!
莫娅 没事的 莫娅
Moya! It does not matter.
你在这儿 上帝保佑
你好 帕特
Hello, Pat.
你好 西妮娅
Hello, Sinéad.
芬巴 什么风把你给吹来的?
What are you doing here on a busy evening?
- 凯瑟琳 - 芬巴 他今晚脾气有点不好
- Catherine. - Finbar. He is grumpy tonight.
- 那个老狗日的?不多见啊 - 是啊 尤其是今晚我还不当班
- The old slambert? Never in my life. - And then on my night out.
给老狗上一大杯啤的 再给他可怜的老婆来杯发泡酒
A big dish for the grumpy stodder, a Babycham for his suffering wife -
还有我的黑布林威士忌 谢啦
- and a Black Bush for me.
你卖那几本破书的钱可经不起这么糟践
You're probably throwing money around. How can you make a living selling books?
只要我还能赢钱 就没问题
As long as I win money from you, I'll be fine.
- 抓到开车的疯子了吗?  - 完全没头绪
- Did you catch the speed devil? - Not at all.
运气不好 但我会逮到他的
I haven't had much luck, but I'll probably get hold of him.
必须的
I believe so.
水 谢谢
Water, please.
- 拉得很棒 孩子  - 谢谢 我的朋友
- Great game. - Thank you my friend.
这是首老歌 寓意是青山不老春常在
It's an old tune. Old as the mountains, but it's always good.
- 你怎么看?  - 当"表演"那么看  - 是啊
- Do you say old as the mountains? - We call it a gig.
- 谢谢 - 你在这里干什么?
- Thanks. - What are you doing over here?
很久以前 一个爱尔兰人来到我的村子
Long ago an Irishman came to my village.
他演奏的曲子无比优美
He played the most beautiful tune I have ever heard.
但我错过了 所以我就跟来了这里
He left before I learned it, so I just had to come.
你不想念吗? 你的家乡?
Don't you miss it? Your home country?
战争和鲜血 我都不想念
I don't miss the games. And I don't miss the blood.
我看到莫娅桥上钓鱼 说在那边吃晚饭
I saw your Moya fishing for dinner by the bridge.
听上去像是她 有主意的很
Sounds like her. She is very opinionated.
我们就像黑夜中擦舷而过的小舟
We are like ships that meet in the night.
- 别对她太苛刻 - 还看到啥了?
- Don't be too hard on her. - What have you?
装渔具的箱子掉水里了
The box of food fell into the water.
- 什么? - 我讲话分散了她的注意力
- What? - I talked and distracted her.
好吧 多谢提醒
Thanks for the warning.
- 小心我的脚 - 早就不会踩了
- Watch my feet. - It's been a hundred years. Quiet now.
这一幕似曾相识啊
I know that look.
你要去哪儿? 我猜不会是因为鱼食掉水里了想跑吧?
Where are you going? I guess you're not running away because of the food. Do you?
我跟你妈妈讲了 都是我的错
I told your mother it was my fault.
你要是骑马跑了的话 你妈妈会很想你的
She's going to miss you terribly when she's left here -
我也会很孤单
- as you ride away.
你是个勇敢的孩子 莫娅 但马不爱走夜路
You are brave, Moya. Because horses don't like the dark.
他们害怕路上的坑洼和突然闪现的小动物
They are terrified of the rabbit holes and the rabbits.
所以最好在白天跑
Better run away during the day -
这样就不会遇到意想不到的事情
- so you don't run into anything unexpected.
当然 一切都随你
But it's up to you. You decide.
- 你还住在大篷车里吗? - 是的
- Do you still live in the caravan? - Yes.
妈妈说房子总也建不起来
Mother says the house will never be finished.
- 快走吧  - 什么?
- Just go now. - What?
- 作为一名绅士怎么能把女士拉在门口呢  - 不用了
A gentleman always follows the lady right to the door.
莫娅 该死的 你去哪儿了? 我饿死了
Moya, damn it! Where have you been? I'm starving.
这是谁?
Who is it?
- 一位绅士 - 喜欢柯蒂斯叔叔吗?
- A gentleman. - Like Uncle Curtis here?
- 你不是我叔叔 - 好好讲话 听懂了没有?
- You are not my uncle. - Speak properly. Are you following?
女人 烦死个人
Women! They really can't stand it.
流浪汉终于回来了
The Wanderer is back.
- 到时候了 - 我已经紧赶慢赶了
- It was about time. - I just waited a bit.
- 这是什么鬼? 苹果? - 我只能弄到这个
- What the hell is this? Apples? - That's what I got.
三个小时 就弄回来点苹果 你在搞什么鬼?
After three hours you come with apples. What are you thinking?
- 闭嘴  - 他怎么会是你哥哥?
- Shut up! - How can he be your brother?
- 口音都不一样 - 不关你的事
- You don't even sound alike. - It is none of your business.
- 你怎么搞的? - 我在大篷车里等莫娅
- What have you done? - I was waiting for Moya.
你不一定非要见她
You don't have to be there.
去拿了东西就回来 明白吗?
Just get what we need and come back. Are you following?
有人在吗
Bank-bank.
哦 是芬巴 谢谢
Finbar, that is. Thanks.
- 有点重 - 进来喝杯茶?
- It's heavy. - A cup of tea?
不了 谢谢
No way.
嘿 莫娅
Hey Moya.
- 你拿的是什么? - 没什么
- What do you have there? - Nothing.
- 也许我应该问问你妈妈 - 不 求你了 别跟他说
- Maybe I should ask your mother. - No, you mustn't say anything to her.
让我看看 让我看看
Let me see. Come on.
你从哪里得到的?
Where did you get it from?
- 你叔叔给你的? - 他不是我叔叔
- Did your uncle give it to you? - He's not my uncle.
他为什么给你这个?
Why did he give it to you?
他对你做了什么 你身上的瘀青怎么来的?
Does it have anything to do with your bruises?
莫娅
Moya.
发生了什么事? 你不想告诉我吗?
Has something happened that you don't want to tell me about?
怎么了?
What?
莫娅
Moya!
好绅士又来了 早上好啊西妮娅 莫娅
There we have the good gentleman again. Good morning, Sinéad. Moya.
你应该对西妮娅没兴趣吧 对你来说年轻了点
You don't care about Sinéad, do you? She is legally young for you.
闭嘴 柯蒂斯 别理他 他就是个混球
Clap in, Curtis. Don't take care of him. He is a fool.
咋了 我就不能和本地人聊两句吗? 交个朋友
Now can't I even have a little chat with the locals? We are good friends.
对不? 我就说嘛
Not too, bass man? Thats how it should be.
- 裸泳完了就是饿呀  - 拿了就走吧
- You get really hungry from nude bathing. - Take it and go.
- 晚上还有 - 我在上面都快疯了
- You'll get more tonight. - I'm going crazy up there.
需要找人聊聊天
I need company.
走了 闪人了 公主
Damn it. See you, princess.
- 老朋友? - 朋友还有得选
- Old friend? - You choose friends.
但该死的亲戚没法选
But not his goddamn in-laws.
我的...
Min...
我哥哥娶了他妹妹 然后被人杀了
My brother married his sister and died soon after.
我盼着他也能快点步他后尘
I look forward to his departure.
我以为你已经金盆洗手了
I thought you had shelved it.
让他做 凯文 我付钱
Give it to him silly Kevin. I pay.
你脑子没进水吧? 对本地人动手
Are you really smart? Here. A local?
- 你想自找麻烦吗?  - 不是本地人
- Do you want the boys in blue running? - He's not from here.
- 他是外地人 叫柯蒂斯  - 你不在乎我在乎
- He comes from outside. Curtis... - I don't care. Not here.
也许他是爱尔兰共和军的 被他们缠上 这辈子都别想消停
Maybe he's from the IRA. You just get them on your neck for the rest of your life.
就这样放任不管 让他继续伤害她吗?
Are you just going to let him hurt her?
- 你又不清楚是不是他干的 - 是他 我能从她的眼睛里看出来
- You don't know what he has done. - Yeah. I can see it in her eyes.
必须让这家伙停手 天呐 她还是个孩子 罗伯特
And this one has to shut her up. She's only a child, Robert!
向警方匿名举报怎么样 嗯?
Stick him to the ropes.
那样的话她什么也不会说的 她很害怕
She doesn't tell them anything. He has scared the wits out of her.
那样还会继续折磨其他无辜的人
He never stops torturing people.
罗伯特 我知道我说过洗手不干 但这次不一样
Robert, I know what I said about killing, but this is different.
我不会参与 芬巴
I won't touch it with fire tongs.
别找我
Forget it.
边走边晾鞋吗?
Are you airing your shoes?
- 你原来会讲话啊? - 不听话时就讲话
- Well, so you can talk? - Only when I'm done listening.
我得去趟西妮娅那里 要不要搭便车
I have to stop by Sinéad. Jump in. You can drive along.
- 你是在度假吗?  - 度假? 算了吧
- Are you on vacation? - Holiday? No, damn it.
我本可以在马略卡岛沐浴阳光 而不是在这里的乡下
I could have been soaking up the sun in Mallorca instead of being out here in the countryside.
手套箱里有烟 拿着吧 底下有火柴
There are cigarettes in the glove compartment. Just take it. There are matches on the floor.
我都不认识路了
The way back never looks the same.
因为这里的山丘 是由巨人创造的
That's because the mountains were created by giants.
真的假的
You do not say.
很久很久以前 弗莫尔人凯尔特神话中的巨人族统治着这片土地
Once upon a time, fomoirs ruled this land.
他们是航海之神
They were godlike sailors.
他们奴役了这片土地 传说中他们专吃小孩
They enslaved the land and ate the children, the legend says.
- 我刚刚在这里放过枪 - 你是猎人?
- But I only use it for shooting. - Are you a hunter?
如果只是射土豆、罐头和野兔的话
If it's shooting for bean cans and prairie hares -
那我就是个厉害的猎人
- then I'm a formidable hunter.
- 你使什么枪? - 福克斯步枪
- What do you have? - A smooth run. Fox.
泰迪(西奥多).罗斯福称它是有史以来最好的枪
Teddy Roosevelt called it the best weapon ever.
你想瞧瞧吗?
Do you want to see it?
在得到这柄珍宝前 我还有一把雷明顿17型手枪
I had a Remington 17 before I got this.
不华丽 也没有精美的雕饰
It was not as delicious and not as beautifully built.
漂亮吧? 想感受感受吗?
Beautiful, right? Will you hold it?
该死
Damn.
操你妈
Satan's.
- 我做了什么? - 小莫娅 你这混蛋
- What have I done to you? - Little Moya, you pig.
我保证消失 我是说 我走了再也不回来了
Before hell. I must disappear. You'll never see me again.
我的老天爷
God damn it.
死吧 你这个老混…
You are the power of death. Stupid pig!
这小子跑得还挺快
There must have been crumbs in that boy.
他为什么会带把刀? 小年轻也会喜欢带这个?
Why did he have a knife? Is this something young men go with?
我不知道其他年轻人在想些什么
I don't know what the young people are doing.
- 你怎么来了? - 罗伯特让我照看照看你
- What are you doing out here? - Robert asked me to look after you.
是吗 还挺有先见之明
Now, so he did?
那麻烦你…
Well then...
小赌怡情
I like banko.
今晚在赖特的小酒馆有宾果游戏 你请我玩
There's banking tonight at Wright's. You pay for my records.
最好再来点小酒
And a dish or two.
我想我有点明白了 那些人为什么要抱怨
Stop it. Now I understand why they whine like that.
之前有个正在挖土的家伙
Once upon a time there was a tumpe who was digging.
挖着挖着他突然明白了
But he knew that when he stopped, it had happened.
自己要完
The terminus.
于是他接着挖
So he kept going.
他得挖了足有三米深 倒下来后他手上的水泡有李子那么大
He must have dug three meters down. He had blisters the size of plums.
他完全可以 一直挖到斐济或是哪儿
He damn well could have made it all the way down to Fiji.
- 我就站在那里大笑起来 - 在你看来 一切都是笑话 对吗?
- I just stood there screaming with laughter. - You're laughing at the whole thing, aren't you?
包括这项工作
This work.
正如我父亲常说的
As my father always said:
"做你喜欢做的事"
"Do something you like."
下一个数字是 53
- Next number: No stress, 53. - Værsgo, Finbar.
- 昨天欠你的 - 没必这样做
- I give in yesterday. - You do not have to.
- 也能请我一个吗? - 你不是被禁言了吗 凯文?
- Can I have a? - Don't you have quarantine?
她挺带劲儿的
She is a wild bass.
她让我想起被我扔进树林里的人
She reminds me of someone I left in the woods.
- 女人?  - 是的
- A woman? - Yes.
他们比男人更沉稳
They are more composed than the men.
你不觉得吗? 死得更有尊严
Do not you think? They die with greater dignity.
- 我的老天 - 你从来没有…?
- You almighty. - Have you never...?
没有 世界上残酷的男人已经够多的了
No. There are enough cruel men.
她也很残酷 看着就怕那种
She was also cruel. Horrible to watch.
- 但哭起来还是让人受不了 - 宾果!
- But the crying got the better of it. - Banko!
- 操 - 你是不是脑子有病
- Satan! - You are a bit strange in the head.
你不说话时还挺好 我只是需要份赚钱的工作
You shouldn't have talked. Just a welcome penny.
但许多人 包括你 还有同情心 这才是病
But so many, as you have necked, it is psychotic.
听着 你这个垃圾
Listen, you piece of shit.
我杀人不是为了好玩 而且我也不干了
I don't kill for fun. And I'm done with it.
但如果我听到你嘲笑一个跪在地上哭泣的人
But if I hear you mocking one who is on his knees weeping…
那我就得揍你了
then I'll beat you with my old fists.
你总共杀了多少人?
How many have you killed in total?
柯蒂斯 你怎么了
Curtis, come now.
柯南呆不下去了
Conan gasps.
他们杀害父亲的那天 柯蒂斯正在校队踢足球赛
The day they murdered our father, Curtis was playing soccer on the boys' team.
毕竟 他也有好人的一面
He wasn't all bad after all.
我永远也忘不了 当我告诉他时他的表情
I will never forget when I told him what had happened.
他就坐在那里直勾勾地盯着我 他啥也不明白
He just sat there staring at me and couldn't understand it at all.
后来 他在贝尔法斯特长大 我和妈妈一起去了南边
He grew up in Belfast and I down south with mum.
他的整个世界都被颠覆了
His whole world was turned upside down.
我答应过他 要照顾他一辈子
I promised him that I would always take care of him.
柯南说我们得离开这里
Conan says we need to get away.
- 去法国 或者… - 没有我哥哥就不行
- Go to France. - Not without my brother.
他可能醉倒在酒吧里了 你知道他的
He's probably stuck in the pub. You know how he is.
除非他会隐身 否则他绝不是在他妈的酒吧过的夜!
Unless he's gone invisible, he hasn't spent the night in the pub!
你觉得我傻吗?
Do you think I'm stupid?
- 没有柯蒂斯 我们哪儿也不去 - 他可能在回老家的路上
- We're not going anywhere without Curtis. - He's probably on his way home.
- 他回老家就死定了 我们都一样  - 对 我知道
He's dead if he goes home. We all are.
"柯蒂斯.朱恩和杜兰.麦肯 报上都有 我就知道他会搞砸的
"Curtis June and Doireann McCann." I knew he would complain.
- 我们搞定那件事了 不是吗?  - 那些小孩子呢
- We got the pigs, didn't we? - What about the children?
- 我怎么知道 - 你们被人看到了 但我和西默斯没有
- I couldn't have known that. - You were seen, but not me and Seamus.
- 他们只从后面看到我们 - 我昨晚从后面看见她了
- They only saw us from behind. - I saw her from behind yesterday.
- 我只是想开个玩笑  - 你要干什么?
- I'm just trying to lighten the mood. - What are you about to do?
出去找那个不想走 只想自个儿呆着的白痴
Out and find the power idiot who just had to keep a low profile.
你们这些胆小鬼想走就走吧
He manages that a little too well. If you wimps want to leave, get out.
但别指望他们会在贝尔法斯特张开双臂迎接你们
But don't expect them to welcome you with open arms in Belfast.
柯蒂斯
Curtis!
- 你来这里干什么? - 柯蒂斯昨天说什么了没有?
- What are you doing here? - Did Curtis say what he had to yesterday?
我昨天没看到他
I didn't see him yesterday.
- 他失踪了吗? - 感谢上帝
- Has he disappeared? - Thank God.
我不该让你进来 收拾收拾赶紧跑路吧
I should never have let you into my life again. Pack your shit and run.
竟敢跟我这么讲话 看我不把你舌头都撕了
Don't talk to me like that. I'll rip your tongue out of your mouth!
也许警察已经抓了他 甚至帮你这人渣把牢房的床都铺好了
Maybe the police caught him. They are probably ready to bang you.
妈妈
Mor!
我们在为爱尔兰人民的自由而战 里面还包括你这坨屎!
I am fighting for a free Ireland. That includes you, you piece of shit!
所以你他妈该对我放尊重点 他对你说了些什么?
So you have the power to just show me some respect. What did he say to you?
妈妈
Mor!
他什么也没说 但我又不傻 我看报纸了
He didn't say anything. But I'm not stupid. I read newspapers.
我没事
I'm fine.
他经常去游泳 说不准淹死了
He used to bathe. Maybe he drowned.
我的老天爷 你是不是不老的神仙?
Godfather! When do you let age catch up with you?
- 战场最能锻炼人了 - 你在哪儿学的枪?
- The front line probably teaches one to shoot. - What's your excuse?
我是最后一批上前线的 可没不像你浴血奋战过
I was one of the last to arrive. I did not experience the horrors of war like you.
对我来说 解放法国 就是跟着队伍瞎乱跑
For me, the liberation of France was just a lot of running around.
- 战后他们没少拿这事儿嘲笑你? - 一直以来都这样
- Did you have to listen to it? - I didn't get any nice words along the way.
我一心想干纳粹王八蛋们
I was intent on fighting the Nazi pigs.
所以我不得不加入英国人的军队
Although I had to side with the English.
这也是我穿这身制服的原因 我知道如何区分对与错
That's why I'm wearing a uniform. I know the difference between right and wrong.
看看北方的局势 如今正是需要警察的时候
And we are needed when you look at the conditions in the north.
我这辈子经历过很多战争
I have experienced plenty of war.
正中目标
Such.
- 他来过吗?  - 没
Has anyone come out here?
- 所以他可能在贝尔法斯特?  - 那我就亲自把他送走
So he might be in Belfast?
- 如果是警察…  - 不可能
What if the police are on our trail?
别扯了 妈的!给我点有用的
Stop it, dammit! Give me something.
当地（地下)组织 姓名 本地消息灵通的人
Local intelligence, names. Someone who knows something.
你在哪儿?
- 你最好藏起来  - 多尼格尔 我们在这有个熟人
Yes. The best hiding places are the ones with completely impossible crap names.
是的 藏在哪儿都不认识的地方最好
- 你带笔了吗  - 有 有
- Yes.
操
Satan's.
不 呆在这儿
No. Stay here.
- 罗伯特.马奎? - 进来都不敲门吗?
- Robert McQue? - Don't you knock?
习惯了
Gammel vane.
你的同行没有具体说是什么事情
Your colleague didn't say what it was about.
他可能害怕电话会被窃听
He was probably afraid that the phone would be tapped.
谨慎得要死
Paranoid fools.
我在找个朋友 需要你这里地下势力的协助
I'm looking for a friend. And no one knows the shadows better than those under the rocks.
很好
It was good.
这位朋友叫什么名字?
What is this friend's name?
柯蒂斯 柯蒂斯.朱恩
Curtis. Curtis June.
- 这名字真有趣 朱恩? - 是的 是
- That was a funny name. June? - Yes. June.
是什么的缩写吗? 是六月(June)吗?
Is it an abbreviation for something? June?
六月是什么简称? 六月就他妈是六月
Whether June is short for something? It's June. Like the month of June.
我从未见过叫这个名字的人
I have never met anyone with that name.
红头发 高个子 瘦瘦的
Red haired, tall, skinny.
真没什么印象
No bell rings. They rascals -
韦斯特匪帮可能知道 要不去问问他们
- out at Inishwest might know something. Talk to them.
你瞧 我这里一团糟 得打扫打扫
I'm going to dry up here.
那么 请自便吧
Can you find out for yourself?
正合适
It fits.
- 我说…  - 我听到了
- I said... - I heard it well.
- 你离我很近 - 他死了吗?
- You are only a meter away. - Is he dead?
应该是
Undoubtedly.
- 与我无关  - 那么是谁呢?
- I had nothing to do with it! - Then who?
- 快说 不然我现在就掀了你脑壳 - 请把枪口挪开
- Say it or I'll pluck you now! - Get it away.
我不会为他冒生命危险
I'm not risking my life for him.
- 我让他别这么做 - 谁?
- I told him not to do it. - Who?
芬巴
Finbar.
芬巴.墨菲 但我们已经拆伙了
Finbar Murphy. But we have gone our separate ways.
- 他不再受雇于此  - 谁下的谋杀令?
- He is no longer employed here. - Who ordered the murder?
- 你去问他好了  - 他住在哪里?
- Ask him. - Where does he live?
我不知道 如果你不介意的话 我想来欣赏欣赏…
I do not know. And now I want to appreciate -
你…
- that you...
罗比?
Robbie?
- 罗比不在了 - 他在哪儿?
- Robbie is no longer here. - Where is he?
我开枪打了他
I shot him.
他自找的 怨不得别人
He asked for it himself. It's not to be disrespectful.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
乔西
Josie.
你的声音很甜美
You have a sweet voice.
你没有做错任何事
You haven't done anything wrong.
但没用的 你看到我的表情了吧?
But it won't work, you see my face, right?
没有
No.
进卧室 把门锁上 呆在那里 直到我离开
Go into your bedroom and lock the door. And stay there until I'm gone.
反正罗比就在那儿
Robbie isn't going anywhere.
拿开
Get it away.
看看这个
Look here.
- 抢来的?  - 好一场屠杀
- Blood money? - It's quite a massacre.
再次谢谢你 丽塔
No, Rita.
哦 等一下
Wait a minute.
我本该亲自教你 但我也记不全了
I'm supposed to teach you how to plant, but I can't remember it all.
书会教你的 你做得很好
Books are a good help. You have done well.
- 我迫不及待想学了 晚安 - 晚安
- It's a start, then. Good night. - Good night.
罗伯特出事了
It's Robert.
- 芬巴  - 马奎夫人  - 感谢您的光临
- Finbar. Thank you for coming. - Finbar!
- 芬巴 - 不 马奎夫人 不要
- Finbar. - No, mrs. McQuay. Do not.
- 罗比是个好人 - 该死的 他才不是
- Robbie was a good man. - God damn it, he wasn't.
他已经倒在地上了 就是个好人
He was good enough at the bottom. Did you see him?
你看到凶手了吗?
是个女的 我没有看到
It was a her. And no, I didn't.
她和罗比谈过话 在找一个叫柯蒂斯的人
- She talked to Robbie. - She was looking for a Curtis.
那个红头发的小伙儿?
The red-haired kid?
- 那她得找把铲子 - 我们不能呆在这里
- Then she needs a shovel. - We can't stay here.
- 好吧 我真讨厌总是等 - 去找点汽油
- Well. I really hate waking up. - Find some gas.
到厨房去
Go out into the kitchen.
- 好的 - 剩下的我来解决
- All right. - I'll probably make it here.
像这种小镇 人人都互相认识
Everyone knows each other in these small towns.
- 为啥要我去问? - 因为你看上去就像个总迷路的人 去吧
- But why me? - Because you always look so lost. Go.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是来拜访我叔叔的
I am here to visit my uncle.
我们有点迷路 你认识芬巴.墨菲吗?
We've gone a little wild. You don't know a Finbar Murphy do you?
芬巴? 是的 我认识
Finbar? Yes, I know him well.
他就住在这里
He lives that way.
该死的
God damn.
晚上好 警官
Good evening, officer.
- 要加满吗? - 是的
- Shall I fill it up? - Yes.
- 之前见过这人没有?  - 没有
- Have you seen him there before? - No.
- 他说要去拜访他的叔叔芬巴  - 芬巴?
He says he has to visit his uncle Finbar.
老家伙从没提过他还有一个侄子
The old fool never mentioned that he has a nephew.
- 芬巴 - 对不起  - 难以置信
- I am sorry. - It's unbelievable.
- 在我们走后报警 - 我知道
- Call the police when we're gone. - I'll do that.
看这个 真漂亮
Look here. Beautiful.
他们是怎么找到他的?
How did they find him?
也许打听到了他的关系网
Maybe he asked his network about him Curtis.
你走后我查了一下柯蒂斯这人
Checked on him after you were there.
我守在外围 需要多长时间?
I'll wait for you outside. How long will it take?
停那儿
Hang in there.
- 有什么问题吗? - 我家进了人
- Did something scare you? - There is someone in my house.
好吧 我想我失业了
Well, I guess I'm unemployed.
罗伯特用我办事 但他这人还行
Robert took advantage of me, but he treated me well.
你们是朋友吗?
Would you say you were friends?
我们有共同点 有共同的秘密
We had things in common. Things that should be kept hidden.
你算是离家出走的?
Did you run away from home?
一个没有爱的家
If it's a crappy home without love, it's unlikely to run away.
不算出走
Rather, it is to escape.
一天晚上 我在
One evening I ended up -
在酒馆里大打出手 我赢了 罗伯特也在场
- in a huge fight in a pub. I won. Robert was there.
他请我喝酒 以30镑一个人的价码雇我做事
He filled me with beer and offered me £30 to push one into the water.
可我当时不知道他能拿130镑 罗伯特这个狡猾的鬼东西
I didn't know he got 130 himself, but that's how Robert was, the sly prankster.
钱来的太容易
It was easy money.
我杀了多少人
I no longer have control over...
我自己也数不清了
how many I have killed.
战争让我变成一个陌生人
The war had turned me into someone I couldn't know.
我回到家 发现我的玛格丽特已经去世
And when I came home and found that my Margaret was dead...
于是那残存的自我 消失进了黑洞
what was left of my old self disappeared into a black hole.
然后罗伯特也入了行
Then came Robert.
就像你说的 太容易
As you said yourself, it was too easy.
领养老金的和他该死的葡萄干
Old people and their lorterosins.
- 如果他不来  - 也可能是在监视我们
- If he doesn't come now... - He's probably watching us.
所以 让我们给他一个惊喜
So let's give him something to look forward to.
不
No.
快回去 丽塔 求你了
Come back in, Rita. Come on.
你一定是个充满好奇的该死的邻居 哈
You must be the curious neighbor.
- 别多管闲事 小心出问题  - 你认识芬巴?
- Take care of yourself, otherwise things will go wrong. - Do you know Finbar?
我从没见过他 但我会的
I've never met him, but I will.
墨菲先生做了不可饶恕的事
Mr. Murphy has done something unforgivable.
- 你在干什么? - 我要杀了她
- What are you doing? - I'll kill her.
- 形势于我们不利  - 形势? 这是战争吗?
- We have not taken over. - Is that war talk?
记住 丽塔不能陷入交火之中
Get it down. Rita must not be caught in the crossfire.
老天 多么荒凉的地方
God, how desolate it is here.
尤其是对你这样一个体弱多病的老人来说
Especially for a frail old man like you.
如果你看到你的朋友 告诉他
If you see your friend, greet him.
告诉他有个满嘴喷粪的婊子在找他?
Greetings from the rap-mouthed bitch.
告诉他
Do it.
- 她找了个疯子女人聊天  - 柯南
- Shut up, you lame bitch. - Conan!
过来
Come on!
上帝啊 抓住她的腿
God. Take her leg.
你先进
You go first.
十字路口旁有两所房子
Two houses from the crossroads.
- 门前种花的那间就是 - 你是谁?
- The thing with the flowers.
我是谁不重要 你是医生 她需要帮助 请尽快去她家
It may not matter. You are a doctor. Now just drive to her house, right?
我们到了
So here we are.
家 甜蜜的家
Home Sweet Home.
好了 乖宝宝
Such. Good cat.
好东西还真不少 难怪你玩个宾果游戏都得我付账!
There is such a fortune. Good, I paid for your bank chargers!
也许我只是想找个人聊聊天
Maybe I just wanted to chat.
- 你弹吗? - 只会几个和弦
- Do you play it? - Just a few chords.
我没受过教育 啥都靠自学
I haven't been taught. It is self-taught.
总有一天 我也会自己出唱片
One day I will record my own record.
兴许会去加利福尼亚出
Maybe over in California -
如果我能凑齐 足够旅费的话
- if I can scrape together enough for the journey.
那里似乎…很自由什么的
People over there just seem... so free or something.
他们享受生活 你明白吗?
They enjoy life. Do you understand?
贝尔法斯特炸弹袭击嫌犯
比赛快开始了 快点
- The match will start soon. - Then came.
我从没见你买过报纸
I've never seen you buy a newspaper.
我从没见你清醒过
I've never seen you sober.
通缉爆炸案的第三名嫌犯
THIRD SUSPECT WANTED IN BOMBING
你好 帕特 还你20块油钱
Hello, Pat. Let me get 20 Gold.
芬巴
Finbar.
这个可怜虫一定是个独行侠 我从没在镇上见过他
The poor wretch must have been a recluse, for I never saw him in town.
他的名字叫罗伯特.马奎
His name was Robert McQue.
认识不?
Did you know him?
女主人说是一个女人杀了他
The mother said a woman killed him.
搞得我一头雾水
I don't know what's up and down in this case.
也许路标被撞也是这人干的
Maybe the road sign had something to do with it?
路标上可能有标记说什么人要来了
Perhaps the road sign indicated that something was coming.
反正调查人员正从都柏林赶来 他们会从我这里接手这个案子
Investigators are coming from Dublin. They'll take over the case, and I'll go.
你从没说过你有个侄子
You never said you had a nephew.
可爱的孩子 我很少见到他
Sweet boy. I don't see much of him.
您是否愿意 把我送到西妮娅家?
Would you like to drop me off at Sinéad's?
进来吧
Jump in.
好了 谢谢你的顺风车 文尼
Now... Thanks for the ride, Vinny.
别把这当做理所当然啊
Now don't get off to a good start.
- 不然我这车就成出租了 - 稳点开
- I must not have favourites. - Drive.
叫我们"隐蔽低调" 而你却在这看他妈的球赛!
"Keep a low profile. Keep hidden." And then you go to a fucking soccer game!
他来了
He comes here.
告密者无处不在
Stingers. They are forceful everywhere.
- 照片没拍好 - 他们在追捕我们 我们得走了
- They didn't get you from your nice side. - They're after us. We have to go.
- 还不到时候 - 每个人都能认得我们 杜兰
- Not yet. - Everyone recognizes us, Doireann.
柯蒂斯死了 试着给逝者一点关爱
Curtis is dead. Just think about it, dammit.
长球
Long ball!
我们去烧了那混蛋的房子 然后去阿姆斯特丹或法国
We burn down the pig's house for Curtis and march to Amsterdam or France.
- 反正也有钱了 - 你没疯吧?
- We have money to start over. - Have you gone insane?
- 离开爱尔兰? 为什么? - 为了生存
- Leave Ireland? What is the purpose then? - To survive.
- 那其他人就是白死了吗? - 等风声过去
- Was their death in vain? - Just until the storm subsides.
难道只有我才明白我们为何而战?
Am I the only one who has understood what we are fighting for?
我们哪儿也不去
We're not going anywhere.
有人雇佣墨菲去杀柯蒂斯 我们得找出是谁
Someone hired Murphy to kill Curtis. We have to find out who.
不管是老太太还是书记员
The old wife, the clerk.
只要有人知道他在哪里 我们就必须逼他说出来
Someone knows where he is. We have to force it out of them.
我去上厕所 你们两个 在我不在的这段时间
I'm going to lokum. You two can soak your empty brains -
用你们空荡荡的脑瓜子想想主意
- while I'm gone.
芬巴
Finbar!
- 哈桑 - 我最忠实的粉丝
- Hassan. - My biggest fan.
你还在这里 感觉还不错吧?
You got stuck. What do you think?
每个人看起来都那么激情 我都不知道该支持谁了
Everyone looks so bloodthirsty. I don't know who to side with.
你好吗?
How are you?
- 还行 莫娅呢?  - 她就在附近
- Fine. What about Moya? - She's here somewhere.
她确定她很安全 她没事
She probably makes up tricks. She's fine.
- 我们没事  - 好吧 再见
- We feel good. - Well. See you.
- 今晚见?  - 好的
- See you tonight? - Yes.
- 芬巴.墨菲?   - 杜安.麦肯?
- Finbar Murphy? - Durian McCann?
朵瑞安
It is pronounced Doireann.
我只在纸上见过你 哪哪都是
I have only seen it in writing. They write about you.
告诉我是谁要杀他 不然我就当场爆你的头
Tell me who ordered the murder or I'll shoot you here in this place of shit.
你也杀了我的朋友 现在我们扯平了
We've killed each other's friends. Let's draw the line.
- 快走吧 然后… - 错错错 操你妈
- Now just go, and then... - Nothing. Hell no.
我杀了一个白痴 而柯蒂斯是我亲哥哥
I killed a freak creep. Curtis was my brother.
那你就该知道他的…癖好
Then you must have known of his... inclinations.
- 告诉我名字  - 放轻松
- Give me the name. - Take it easy.
我可以带他去找你 这更容易
I can lead him to you. It is easier.
- 你要让他投降吗?  - 是我让柯蒂斯上的车
- Do you just make him surrender? - I then got Curtis into the car.
八点在这里等我 不会有人知道
Meet me here at eight o'clock. Nobody's going to see anything.
你是觉得我他妈傻吗?
You can damn well believe no. Do you think I am stupid?
- 我们在酒馆见  - 赖特的?
- We'll meet at the pub. - Wright's?
没错 挤满了快乐的客人
Exactly. It is packed with happy guests -
他们都不知道你他妈是个杀人犯 别想玩花样
- and none of them know you're a fucking murderer, so no numbers.
我不想你伤害任何人
You do not harm others.
你们要么来 要么 多尼戈尔就会被炸成废墟
You are coming. Otherwise, the pub will be spread across Donegal.
如果我们遭遇不测 会有比我更糟糕的人
If something happens to us, there will be others far worse than me.
他们会搜遍这个荒凉的地方 包括
They end up in this godforsaken place. And the strange, curious -
你那个爱管闲事的邻家女子
- lady next door, you have? No one can be sure.
没人可以逃脱
该死的白痴
Damn idiot!
你拿了我的枪 招呼不打就溜了?
You take my gun and slip away without a sound?
- 很会挑事儿嘛 - 我已经找到了那个领头的
- You have a good sense of drama. - I have found the leader.
她不想罢手
She was not part of a truce.
所以我只能赶尽杀绝
She gave me no choice. I'll kill her.
- 一锅端  - 有什么计划?
- All of them. - How do you intend to do it?
我会公开透明的干这件事
It will be good and public.
所以 要报仇找我 别来这镇子了
So if anyone wants revenge, they go after me and leave the city alone.
你不要参与 我不会有事的
Just drive. I will be fine.
得了吧 伙计
Forget it, mate.
芬巴.墨菲要开战了 我怎么能错过!
The great Finbar Murphy is going to war. I don't want to miss that!
好宝宝
Good cat.
有人吗
Bank-bank.
莫娅 给你的小礼物
Moya. A little gift for you.
想要吗? 他是你的了
Do you want him? He is yours.
- 他叫什么?  - 我没给他起过名
- What's his name? - I never gave him a name.
- 你想叫他什么?  - 他看起来像...肖恩
- What do you think? - He looks like a... Seán.
对他好点 好吗?
Now be good to him, won't you?
做好人很好 就算被他挠了也没关系
It's good to be good, even if it hurts.
这样你就能保持你的善良本性 好吗
Then you preserve your humanity.
再见 肖恩
Farvel, Sean.
你需要观众
You wanted an audience.
我在里面和他们见面 告诉他们他在后面
I meet them in there and tell them I have him out back.
我在那里埋伏着 创造有利形势
Where I wait for them. Then you have taken over.
瞧瞧我带了啥
See for yourself. I listened.
别
No.
我有自己的优势
I have my own upper hand.
走吧 拿着这个
Smut then. Take it here.
包前面有一个信封 把它交给罗伯特的母亲
There is an envelope in the front pocket. Give it to Robert's mother.
- 剩下的就给你了 - 你在干什么? 我们说好的
- The rest is yours. - What are you up to? We agreed...
我们没有达成任何一致 听着 这里没你事了
We didn't agree on anything. Listen up. You have nothing more to do here.
这是我的战争 拿着钱
This is my war. Take the money.
当它是我留给你的遗产 别再弄险了
Let it be my legacy to you. You don't need to use it again.
你还年轻 还有更好的选择
You are young. Find something else.
去加利福尼亚吧 别总想着当圣人
Go to California. You don't have to be a saint.
不要枉送性命
Just don't waste your life on this.
从来没人送过我任何东西
Nobody ever gave me anything.
我的建议更有价值 比钱更重要 相信我
My advice is worth far more than the money. Trust me.
去吧
Smut then.
- 你今晚会害怕吗  - 我的心早已古井无波
- You must be nervous tonight. - Think of my old heart.
但脑瓜子还灵活的很 来吧 我们坐在这里
You are young at heart. Came. We're sitting over here.
敌人可能藏在任何地方
The enemy lurks everywhere.
他不会动手 人太多了
He didn't try anything on the field. Not with all those people.
我进去看看 柯南 你拿着包进来
I go in and look. Conan, you come in with the bag.
- 为什么让他去?  - 因为你的枪法太差了
- Why him? - Because you shoot badly.
找柯蒂斯的时候 没有你我一样搞定了
When I was looking for Curtis, you didn't help and I got the deal done.
因为我已经他妈的 下!令!了!
And because I say so, dammit!
- 好的好的 - 车别熄火
- Yes Yes. - Keep the engine running.
有任何问题 开炸弹定时器 随时走人 明白?
If there's a problem, you set the timer and we'll go, got it?
- 干死这群混蛋  - 半个镇子的人都在里面
- We are killing the pigs. - Half the city is there.
他们想让我们为那些小孩的死抵罪
Some of them can trap us for the dead cubs.
我希望今晚能安静点 我们好吹吹牛
I had hoped for a quiet evening. A few stories, you know.
- 你的俄国书读得怎么样了?  - 还没看完
- How is your Russian book going? - I haven't finished it.
我想你肯定会喜欢的
I think you would like it.
- 悬疑类的? - 没错
- Some mystery and suspense? - Yes.
讲一个精明的侦探 调查一起可怕的谋杀案
A cunning detective investigates a gruesome murder.
他的名字叫波菲利
His name is Porphyry.
他坚持不懈地寻找真相
他堅持不懈地尋找真理......
He is persistent in his search for the truth…
他找到了嫌疑人 了解到他有多么孤独
and force out of the suspect how devastating the isolation is for him.
痛苦吞噬着他
It eats him up.
他让侦探明白 唯一能阻止他的人
He makes him understand that the only one who can stop it -
只能是嫌疑人自己
- is himself.
所以这个侦探的直觉很敏锐?
So he has good instincts, this detective?
他让我想起了你
He actually reminds me of you.
- 他最终能抓住嫌犯吗? - 还不知道
- Will he get hold of his man? - I do not know.
你的侄子今晚会来吗? 还是已经走了?
Is your nephew coming tonight or has he moved on?
你不是卖书的吧 芬巴?
You don't make a living selling books. Well, Finbar?
你到底是做什么的?
What do you actually do?
文尼...
Vinny...
- 你不会想知道的 - 告诉我 我能帮上忙
- You do not want to know that. - Say something and let me help.
不 文尼 你不能
No, Vinny. You can not do that.
莫娅 过来 你得回家去 这里小朋友不能来
Moya! Come here. You must go home. Children are not allowed here.
- 我妈妈说可以的 - 今晚不行
- I feel good for mother. - Not tonight.
- 妈妈要见见肖恩 - 今晚不行 快带肖恩回家吧
- Mother has to see Seán. - Not tonight. Take Seán and go home.
明天再带肖恩来看你妈妈 好吗 回家吧 快!
Seán can meet your mother another day. Okay? Then go home. Now!
来一段!
Play for us!
- 今晚人真多啊  - 是的
- It's going well. - Yes.
你的伙伴呢? 你说过不搞花样的
And your co-conspirators? No numbers, you said.
他们就在附近
They are nearby.
把那混球指给我看 然后你可以去听音乐了
Then let me see the pig so you can go back to your music.
我们在后面碰头
We'll meet out back.
你敢动一下 我就当场崩了你
If you move, I'll pick you on the spot.
好吧
Well.
- 音乐如此美妙 让人充满愉悦 不是吗?  - 啥?
Don't you just love how a song can fill your heart with joy?
音乐啊
The music.
我只是有种冲动 想亲吻她脸颊的冲动
You really want to find the nearest herring and smack her.
你找打是吧? 我对你来说是不是有点太老了?
Is this how you tumps cure? Aren't I a little too old for you?
只要是新鲜的女人 我都会…朵瑞安
I nab any woman who is fresh... Doireann.
谢谢你的礼物 芬巴 成为圣人之前是不是都得犯点罪?
Thanks for the gift, Finbar. But a saint must sin first, right?
- 是他吗?  - 闭嘴
- Is it him? - Shut up.
放松点 当然是我 要不我们去后面吧
Of course it's me. Shouldn't we go out the back...?
蹲下
Ned!
操!
Pis!
快跑
Hurry up!
操了
Satan's.
这是我的东西 混球
It's mine, you stupid pig.
那婊子居然开枪打我
The bitch shot me!
来吧
Come on.
我还在这里呢 朵瑞安
So I'm still here, Doireann!
老天爷啊 你为啥又跑回来了?
You almighty. Why the hell did you come back?
趴下
Get down!
你的钱都在我车里
All your money is in my car.
我猜你会比我先到加利福尼亚
I guess you'll get to California before me.
芬巴
Finbar...
你在寻求救赎吗?
Is he going to save you?
我不需要救赎
I'm not the one to be saved.
我已经做了我该做的 我有我的理由
I have done what I have done. And there was a reason for that.
主很清楚
The Lord knows that well.
你无法评判我
Don't judge me.
我不是来评判的
I'm not here to judge.
我们都有自己的理由
We all have our reasons.
开枪吧
Now just shoot me.
你的路已经走到头了 请求宽恕吧
You are at the end of the road. Now make peace.
我哥哥...
My brother...
他孤身一人走了
He is all alone.
我保证你会去陪他
I'll see to it that you meet him.
他们没抓到你
The bullies didn't hit you.
丽塔 我非常抱歉
Rita, I'm terribly sorry.
没事的 芬巴
It's all right, Finbar.
- 你从没问过我是干什么的 - 我应该吗?
- You never asked what I do for a living. - Should I?
真可惜 啥都没长出来 按理早就该长东西了
It's a shame, nothing will grow. I should have started a long time ago.
不 你留着吧
Keep it.
下次再试试也许运气会好一点
Maybe you'll try your luck again another time.
再见 丽塔
Goodbye, Rita.
保重…自己 对吗?
Take care... of yourself, right?
陀思妥耶夫斯基著 《罪与罚》
Crime and Punishment
全剧终
-END-